Guide to the University Historical Material records, 1821-2012 RG0031
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Early Columbian College, 1822-1961; RG0031 Series 3; 31 Linear feet (Box 153, Box 152, Box 149, Box 150, Box 151, Box 148, Box 176, Box 175, Box 174, Box 173, Box 172, Box 177, Box 171, Box 162, Box 137, Box 169, Box 170, Box 167, Box 157, Box 168, Box 165, Box 155, Box 166, Box 156, Box 161, Box 
  - Columbian College: Accounting book, Preparatory School, 1876-1892 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    This ledger is the accounting book for the Preparatory School at Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1876-1892. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Accounting book, Preparatory, 1894-1897 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    This ledger is the accounting book for the Preparatory School at Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1894-1897. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Accouting book, Corcoran Scientific School, 1894-1896 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    This ledger is the accounting book for the Corcoran Scientific School at Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1894-1896. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Accounting book, Graduate School, 1893-1896 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    This ledger is the accounting book for the Graduate School at Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1893 to 1896. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1871-1872, 09/1871-1872 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 1891-1872. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1872-1873, 10/1872 --05/1873 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 10/1872 to 05/1873. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1873-1874, 10/1873 --05/1874 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 10/1873 to 05/1874. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1880-1881, 10/1880 --05/1881 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 10/1880 to 05/1881. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1881-1882, 10/1881-05/1882 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 10/1881 to 05/1882. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Law School, registration/ payment record, 1884-1888, 10/09/1884 --05/1888 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    This folder contains documents concerning the Law School registration and payment records at Columbian College. They range in date from 10/09/1884 to 05/1888. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, Constitution and by-laws [1857]-1873 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the constitution and by-laws for the Enosinian Society. These records range in date from 1857 to 1873. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, Minutes, includes constitution and by-laws, lists, debate questions, 1834-1841 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes, constitution, by-laws, lists, debate questions, and signatures from the Enosianian Society of the Columbian College. These materials range in date from 1834 to 1841. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, minutes, 1852-1857 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. The materials range in date from 1852 to 1857. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, minutes, 1857-1870 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. The materials range in date from 1857 to 1870. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, constitution and by laws (incomplete), 1857 -1870 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the incomplete constitution and by-laws for the Enosinian Society of the Columbian College. There are no dates for these materials. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, minutes, 1885-1895 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Enosinian Society for the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1885 to 1895. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, minutes, 1896-1899 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Enosinian Society for the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1896 to 1899. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, minutes, 1896, 03/05/1896 --03/27/1896 (Box 147, Folder 3)
    This folder contains two meeting minutes for the Enosinian Society for the Columbian College. The minutes are from the March 5, 1896 and the March 27, 1896 meetings. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, rolls, 1881-1884 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    This folder contains the Enosinian Society's rolls with lists of members who attended each meeting. These records range in date from 1881-1884. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, rolls, includes list of officers and committees, and minutes for 1904-1905 (Box 147, Folder 5)
    This folder contains the Enosinian Society's rolls with lists of members who attended each meeting and also a list of officers and committees. These records range in date from 1904-1905. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, 1905 (Box 147, Folder 6)
    This folder contains notes from the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records range in date from 1905. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, rolls and minutes, 1905-1907 (Box 147, Folder 7)
    This folder contains rolls and minutes from the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records range in date from 1905-1907. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, account book, 1884-1886 (Box 148, Folder 1)
    This folder contains the account book for the Enosinian Society at Columbian College. It includes members' names and their accounts. Records in this ledger range in date from 1884 to1886. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, record of debates, 1822-1831 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    This folder contains records of debates of the Enosinian Society from the Columbian College. Information includes the question at issue, the debator's name, the date, and his/her position. These records range in date from 1822-1831. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, library record, 1852-1872 (Box 148, Folder 4)
    This ledger contains the library records for the Enosinian Society at Columbian College. These records range in date from 1852-1872. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, library record, 1872-1887 (Box 148, Folder 5)
    This ledger contains the library records for the Enosinian Society at Columbian College. These records range in date from 1872-1887. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1838-1844 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter which was produced by the Enosinian Society of the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1838 to 1844. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1845-1855 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter which was produced by the Enosinian Society of the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1854 to 1855. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1883, 03/1883 --04/1883 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the "Enosinian Bee" newletter, which was produced from the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from March through April 1883. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1883, 05/1883 --09/1883 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the "Enosinian Bee" newletter, which was produced from the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from May through September 1883. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1883, 09/1883 --11/1883 (Box 150, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the "Enosinian Bee" newletter, which was produced from the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from September through November 1883. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", January- February 1884, 01/1884 --02/1884 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    This ledger is the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter produced by the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from January through February 1884. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", March- April 1884, 03/1884 --04/1884 (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1887 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    This folder contains the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter produced by the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date to 1887. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1901-1902 (Box 151, Folder 4)
    This ledger is the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter that was produced by the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from 1901 to 1902. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Bee", 1902-1903, 10/1902 -1903 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    This folder contains pages from the "Enosinian Bee" newsletter that was produced by the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. These records date from 1902 to 1903. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, "Enosinian Catalogue", 1859 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    This folder contains the "Enosinian Catalogue" that was produced by the Enosinian Society of Columbian College. It details a history of the group and lists members between 1822 to 1859. These booklet was published in 1859. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Enosinian Society, wooden shield, 1822, 1822 ca. (Box 151, Folder 7)
    This is a wooden shield with the Enosinian Society name, emblem, and the year 1822 painted in gold on it. Also included are metal screws. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes 1863-1869 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1863 to 1869. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes 1869-1876 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1869 to 1876. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes 1877-1879 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1877 to 1879. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes 1879-1881 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1879 to 1881. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes 1881-1884 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1881 to 1884. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes, 1894-1895 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1894 to 1895. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, minutes, 1895-1896, 09/1895 --06/1896 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    This ledger is the meeting minutes for the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. It ranges in date from September 1895 to June 1896. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, library record, 1867-1874 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the library record for the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1867 to 1874. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, Catalogue, 1895-1896, 1895 ca. --1896 -- --ca. (Box 153, Folder 4)
    This folder contains loose pages of notes for the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. They range in date from 1895 to 1896. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, "Hermesian Casket", 1861-1865, 04/24/1861 --04/07/1865 (Box 153, Folder 5)
    This ledger is the "Hermesian Casket", a publication produced by the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. Records range in date from April 24, 1861 to April 7, 1865. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Hermesian Society, "Hermesian Casket", 1860-1872 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    This folder contains loose pages of the "Hermesian Casket", a publication produced by the Hermesian Society at the Columbian College. Records range in date from 1860-1872. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Philophrenian Society, Minutes, 1867-1876 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes from the Philophrenian Society at Columbian College. It ranges in date from 1867 to 1876. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Philophrenian Society, Roll, 1866-1873 (Box 154, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the lists of members from the Philophrenian Society at Columbian College from 1866 to 1873. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Philophrenian Society, library record, 1856-1874 (Box 155, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the library records for the Philophrenian Society at Columbian College. They range in date from 1856 to 1874. Formerly Acc#279.
  - Columbian College: Philophrenian Society, "Philophrenian Spectator", 1855-1858 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the "Philophrenian Spectator" a newsletter from the Philophrenian Society, at Columbian College. These records range in date from 1855 to 1858. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Constitution and code of ethics, 1878-1896 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the constitution and code of ethics for the National College of Pharmacy. Also included are the signatures of members subscribing to the constitution. Materials range in date from 1878-1896. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Pharmaceutical Association, minutes, 1865-1871 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes of the Pharmaceutical Association at the National College of Pharmacy. Also included in this ledger are the lists of officers and members of the Association. Materials range in date from 1865-1871. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board minutes, 1872-1879, Pharmaceutical Association, minutes, 1871-1873, 1871 -1879 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the meeting minutes of the Pharmaceutical Association at the National College of Pharmacy. They range in date from 1871-1873. Also included in this ledger are the Board minutes of the National College of Pharmacy from 1872-1879. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board minutes, 1879-1891, 04/1879 --11/1891 (Box 158, Folder 4)
    This ledger contains the Board minutes of the National College of Pharmacy. Materials range in date from 1879-1891. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board minutes, 1891-1904 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the board minutes of the National College of Pharmacy. Dates range from 1891 to 1904. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board minutes, 1905-1906 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the board minutes of the National College of Pharmacy. Dates range from 1905 to 1906. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1908-1909, 10/05/1907 --12/07/1909 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. They range in date from 1907 to 1909. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1910, 01/04/1910 --12/28/1910 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These minutes are from the year 1910. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1910, 01/03/1911 --12/05/1911 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These minutes are from the year 1911. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1912-1913, 01/02/1912 --12/09/1913 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1912 to 1913. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1914, 01/06/1914 --12/01/1914 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials date to 1914. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1915, 01/05/1915 --12/07/1915 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials date to 1915. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1916, 01/04/1916 --12/05/1916 (Box 161, Folder 7)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials date to 1916. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1917, 01/02/1917 --12/22/1917 (Box 161, Folder 8)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials date to 1917. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, 1918-1919, 01/08/1918 --10/28/1919 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1918 to 1919. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes, includes student grades, 1920-1926, 05/24/1920 --09/14/1926 (Box 161, Folder 10)
    This folder contains board minutes for the National College of Pharmacy. Also included are students' grades in Pharmacy school. These materials range in date from 1920 to 1926. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes (copies), including student grades, 1907-1914 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains copies of the Board Minutes, including reports of student grades, from the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1907 to 1914. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Board Minutes (copies), including student grades, 1915-1925 (Box 162, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains copies of the Board Minutes, including the constitution, by-laws and reports of student grades, from the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1915 to 1925. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: contibutions, 1872-1876 (Box 162, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains records of contributions made to the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1872-1876. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Corresondence,1878-1889, 05/16/1878 --11/04/1889 (Box 163, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains correspondence concerning the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1878 to 1889. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Corresondence,1889-1898 (Box 163, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains correspondence concerning the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1889 to 1898. Formerly Acc#279.
  - National College of Pharmacy: Matriculation and registration, 1894-1903 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains student registration and matriculation records for the National College of Pharmacy. These materials range in date from 1894 to 1903. Formerly Acc#279.
  - University Council: Minutes, includes President's Council and Faculty minutes, 1906-1907, 10/1906 --06/1907 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the University Council minutes for the George Washington University. They include the President's Council and faculty minutes. These materials range in date from 1906 to 1907. Formerly Acc#279.
  - University Council: Minutes, includes President's Council and Faculty minutes, 1907-1908, 10/1907 --05/1908 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    This ledger contains the University Council minutes for the George Washington University. They include the President's Council and faculty minutes. These materials range in date from 1907 to 1908. Formerly Acc#279.
  - University Council: Minutes, includes President's Council and Faculty minutes, 1908-1909, 10/1908 --03/1909 (Box 164, Folder 3)
    This ledger contains the University Council minutes for the George Washington University. They include the President's Council and faculty minutes. These materials range in date from 1908 to 1909. Formerly Acc#279.
  - University Council: Minutes,1909-1910, 10/1909 --01/1910 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    This ledger contains the University Council minutes for the George Washington University. They range in date from 1909-1910. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: President's Council, minutes, 1909-1917, 09/1909 --04/1917 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    This hardcover book contains the records of the minutes from the President's Council at George Washington University. Records range in date from 1909 to 1917. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: President's Council, minutes, 1917-1922, 10/1917 --06/1922 (Box 165, Folder 2)
    This folder contains the records of the minutes from the President's Council at George Washington University. Records range in date from 1917 to 1922. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: President's Council, minutes, 1923-1928, 01/1923 --05/1928 (Box 165, Folder 3)
    This hardcover book contains the records of the minutes from the President's Council at George Washington University. Records range in date from 1923 to 1928. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: President's Council, minutes, copies, 1927-1928, 1927 -05/1928 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    This folder contains the copies of the minutes from the President's Council at George Washington University. Records range in date from 1927 to 1928. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: Dean's Council, minutes, 1908-1910 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    This folder contains the minutes from the Dean's Council at George Washington University. Records range in date from 1908 to 1910. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: Faculty, Department of Arts and Sciences, minutes, 03/12/1904 --05/23/1906 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    This ledger contains the minutes from the faculty of the Department of Arts and Sciences. This includes the Columbian College and Graduate Studies Faculty minutes (see University Council for 1906-1909). These records range in date from 1904 to 1906. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: Faculty, Department of Arts and Sciences, minutes, 1915-1922, 11/06/1915 --05/31/1922 (Box 166, Folder 2)
    This folder contains the minutes from the faculty of the Department of Arts and Sciences. This includes the Columbian College and Graduate Studies Faculty minutes (see University Council for 1906-1909). These records range in date from 1915 to 1922. Formerly Acc#279.
  - George Washington University: Faculty, Department of Arts and Sciences, minutes, 1923-1927, 02/10/1923 --06/02/1927 (Box 166, Folder 3)